Hello English learners, welcome back to
English Pod. My name is Marco and I'm
Erica and today we're gonna go back to
the movies but this time we're gonna do
it a little bit different. That's right
we're gonna be listening as two movie
critics offer their opinion on the
latest release. All right so we're gonna be
learning how to criticize or give your
opinions about something. That's right
and here we're talking movies but a
lot of this language can be used to offer
your criticism or ideas on literature
or art or other artistic pursuits.
Okay so before we listen to this dialogue
for the first time let's take a look at
vocabulary preview. Very cablery preview.
Well we're gonna look at one word
here that we will hear in the dialogue
and it is erudites. Erudite. Erudite.
Okay so this word erudite. Some people
pronounce it erudite. That's true and
basically it's an adjective describing
someone who has a lot of knowledge about
a subject. Okay so an
erudite in engineering.
Yes or an erudite professor.
Okay very good. So that's the word that
we're gonna preview today and now let's
listen to our dialogue and find
out what movie they are criticizing.
Welcome back movie lovers to another
premiere movie review. My name is Richard
Clark and I am joined today by the very
erudite David Watson. Thank you Dick.
Today we're going to talk about the
movie Lion King. Tell me what is your
impression of this film? Well I
think this film is simply a fable.
The picked-thing man's eternal greed for
power and in my opinion it's a very fine
film. Even despite the accusations of
plagiarism of traditional folk tales from
other countries the musical score was
amazing. The animation was very well
done and the story was simply enchanting.
I think otherwise even though the
animation was technically strong and as
you say the score and songs performed by
Elton John were great the film lacks
certain originality it lacked heart and I
would dare to say it was too predictable.
Predictable how come on Dave it's a
g-rated movie it's for the kids it's
not a thriller. Well that's just it. It did
have some very dramatic and intense
scenes for example when Mufasa dies or the
dark grim portrayal of scar. Even so
the film is linear. Mufasa dies. Simba runs
the way thinking it's his fault.
Fause and love and returns to retake what's
rightfully his. It's just too cliche.
How can it be cliche? It's a fable.
It's telling a time-honored story. The
movie makes a point of how the hunger of
power leads to corruption and teaches
children of the value of respect. Life and
love. You have always been so soft dick.
Open your heart Dave. Don't shut us out.
Anyway that's all for today folks join
us next time as we talk about how to
lose a guy in 10 days.
I'm sure you'll love that one.
All right so the Lion King one of my
all-time favorites. A very good movie and
well mixed feelings about it right some
people think it's good other people's
other people think it's not that good.
I'm in the good camp as you know but
anyway there's tons of really useful
and quite difficult language here so why
don't we look at that now in a
language takeaway. Language takeaway.
All right on language takeaway today
we have five words and we can start with
the first one. So the critic the
first critic said that this was a movie
depicting man's eternal greed for power.
Depicting to depict. All right so this
word depict it sounds a little bit strange
so before we explain it let's take a
look at some examples. Example one.
I don't really like the way that novel
depicted the role of women in society.
It was pretty sexist.
Example two. The film depicts
the realities of war very accurately.
Example three. So this image here is
depicting some of the most well-known
scene from Australian history.
All right so depicting I can basically
understand that this
means to show something.
Now if now we
can notice that the
word depict has this short little word
picked in there that sounds like picture.
And when we think about depicting
we're often thinking about in a
picture or in a book or in a painting.
So in this case the story is depicted in a
movie right that's right so you
can see it it's a picture basically.
Exactly. All right very good so to depict
what moving on the critic also talked
about the grim portrayal of the
villain of the movie Scar. That's right so
grim portrayal. A grim portrayal.
Okay let's look at the word grim first.
When something is grim it's really unpleasant
or uncomfortable or even shocking to
think about. Okay so something
that is grim. Now what about portrayal?
Really close to depict a portrayal is
something that shows or describes something
especially like in a book or in a
picture or in a play. Okay so a portrayal I
guess we can relate it again to a portrait.
That's right all right so portrayal.
Now we can also use this as a verb to
portray. So this movie portrays man's
eternal greed. Okay so we can use this
as a noun or as a verb. That's right so
moving on with our third word today
we have an enchanting movie. That's right
the story was simply enchanting.
Okay so if something is enchanting it's
really it's really attractive and beautiful
and interesting and it holds your
attention. Okay it holds your attention
so it's something very nice. Something
that is enchanting has to be nice.
That's right and it has the sense of magic
around it. Okay very good so an
enchanting moment or an enchanting woman.
Okay and now what about our next word it's
a very and what about our next word it's
French actually but we use it in English.
That's right so the critics said that
this story was cliche. Cliche. Cliche.
Okay so we hear this all the time.
What is a cliche? Well basically a cliche
is a phrase or an idea that is used so
often that it loses its meaning or
importance or interest. Okay so can you give
us some examples of a cliche
moment or maybe a phrase that's cliche?
Okay well how about this one when you're
breaking up with your boyfriend and you say
honey it's not you it's me. Okay
that's cliche it's typical. Yep or maybe a
cliche portrayal of a French man would
be a guy riding a bike with a baguette
smoking a cigarette and with a
burey on his head. Okay that's a cliche
portrayal very good. So it's common
it's even to a certain point a little bit
stereotypical. That's right. All right
and what about our last word? Well they
describe this story as a fable. Fable.
Fable. Okay so when we were small we
all read fables. That's right they are
stories about animals that are used to
teach people lesson. Okay so if fable
teaches you a lesson I think the most famous
one is the one of the tortoise and the hair
right. Yeah and another good one would be
the three little pigs. Okay that's also
a fable. Yep. Okay so we've looked at
these five great words and now it's time
for us to move on to putting it together.
Putting it together. Okay here we're
gonna look at some phrases that you
can use in a bunch of different ways
to help you criticize or give your opinion
about a piece of art like a movie or a
book or whatever. Okay so let's start
right away with our first word.
So the film critics asked what is your
impression of this film? What's your
impression of? What's your impression of
something right? That's right.
All right so before we get into explaining
impression let's listen to some more
examples. Example one. I don't know
where but I have the impression that we
have met before. Example two. I get the
impression that he's a very organized
person. Example three. Somehow Jim got the
impression that I was gay. Did you
tell him that? Okay so I can see that this
means basically what's your opinion or
how do you feel about something? Okay so
you can have an impression of something
or of someone. Yep. All right and what
about the next word? Well the critic
Richard Clark said that it was a really
enjoyable film even despite the accusations
of plagiarism. Okay so now we have an
interesting phrase here. The accusations
of plagiarism. Accusations of plagiarism?
Okay so accusations is a noun right?
Right it's the action of accusing. Okay of
blaming somebody. Yeah all right and
what about plagiarism? This is an academic
term. If you a plagiarize you copy someone's
work and take credit for it. Okay so
if I copy somebody's book and I say I wrote
it then that's plagiarism. Yeah that's
pretty bad. So accusations of plagiarism.
Now we can use this phrase accusations of
something in a bunch of different
ways. So Marco let's have an example.
All right so for example we can say
he was cleared of all accusations of tax
evasion. Okay he denied accusations of
cheating on his wife. All right very good
so accusations. And now moving on
to the final part of putting it together we
have this word lacks. The film lacks a
certain originality. Okay so the film lacks a
certain originality. What does he mean
by that? It doesn't have enough of. Okay so
if you are lacking something you don't
have enough of it. Or you don't have it
at all. All right so can you give us some
more examples of how we can use lack.
Okay the same way it's used in the
dialogue. Our team lacks the appropriate
talent to complete this project. Okay or
I can say our school lacks infrastructure
for so many students. Or we can also say
infrastructure is lacking at our school.
Okay so you can use it in those
two ways right you can use it as a
gerund or as a verb. That's right. Okay
lots of great language here and why don't
we hear it one more time in context with
the dialogue. Welcome back movie lovers
to another premiere movie review.
My name is Richard Clark and I am joined
today by the very erudite David Watson.
Thank you Dick. Today we're going to
talk about the movie Lion King. Tell
me what is your impression of this film?
Well I think this film is simply a fable.
The picked-thing man's eternal
greed for power and in my opinion
it's a very fine film. Even despite the
accusations of plagiarism of traditional
folk tales from other countries the
musical score was amazing. The animation
was very well done and the story was
simply enchanting. I think otherwise.
Even though the animation was technically
strong and as you say the score and
songs performed by Elton John were great
the film lacks certain originality.
It lacked heart and I would dare to say it
was too predictable. Predictable
how? Come on Dave it's a g-rated movie.
It's for the kids. It's not a thriller.
Well that's just it. It did have some very
dramatic and intense scenes for
example when Mufasa dies or the dark grim
portrayal of scar. Even so the film is
linear. Mufasa dies. Simba runs away
thinking it's his fault. Falls in love and
returns to retake what's rightfully his.
It's just too cliche. How can
it be cliche? It's a fable. It's
telling a time-honored story. The movie
makes a point of how the hunger of power
leads to corruption and teaches children
of the value of respect. Life and love.
You have always been so soft dick.
Open your heart Dave. Don't shut us out.
Anyway that's all for today folks.
Join us next time as we talk about how to
lose a guy in ten days.
I'm sure you'll love that one's dick.
Alright so a good movie. What do you think
about the Lion King? What do you think
about his critique? Well I am with
dick on this one. I think that this is a
great film. It was one of my favorites
and I've seen it about five billion times.
Really? Yeah. You really liked it. But
I'm not interested in my opinion. I want to
hear criticisms and film criticisms from
our users. Right so come to our website at
EnglishPod.com where you can leave
your questions or comments and also any
criticisms on this particular movie or
maybe the other one that we mentioned
how to lose a guy in ten days. Personally
not so fond of that one but looking
forward to hearing from our users. Alright
or maybe any other movies you might like.
So come to the website
and until next time. Goodbye!